# JINMING SU (苏金明)

Beijing, China

**■** sujinming@meituan.com · **६** (+86) 188-1172-6607

#### ABOUT

I currently work as an algorithm engineer at **Meituan**. I am broadly interested in solving real-world visual understanding problems with optimization/learning-based algorithms. Recently, I focus on developing learning and optimization frameworks for **scene understanding** and **3D reconstruction**.

I obtained my Master's Degree (CS) in State Key Laboratory of Virtual Reality Technology and Systems, SCSE, Beihang University, adviced by Prof. Jia Li, in Jan. 2020. From 2018 to 2019, I worked as a research assistant at Peng Cheng Laboratory with Dr. Changqun Xia. Before that, I received Bachelor's Degree (CS) from SCSE, Northeastern University, in Jul. 2017.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Meituan, Beijing, China

2020 - Present

Algorithm Engineer (L6) 2020 – 2022

Algorithm Engineer (L7) 2022 - Present

Focusing on scene understanding in HD/ADAS/SD Map and 3D vision.

#### **EDUCATION**

### Beihang University (BUAA), Beijing, China

2017 - 2020

M.Sc. in Computer Science and Technology, ranked 9/303, top 3.0%

- State Key Laboratory of Virtual Reality Technology and Systems, SCSE
- Thesis: 场景和任务引导的图像显著内容解析
- Advisor: Prof. Jia Li

#### Northeastern University (NEU), Shenyang, China

2013 - 2017

B.Eng. in Computer Science and Technology, ranked 10/258, top 3.9%

- Thesis: 基于移动终端的室外场景语义分割方法与系统
- Advisor: Prof. Bin Zhang
- Recommended for admission to Beihang University without exams

#### **■** SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- Jia Li, <u>Jinming Su</u>, Changqun Xia, Yonghong Tian. Salient Object Detection with Purificatory Mechanism and Structural Similarity Loss. *IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (T-IP)*, 30, pp.6855-6868, 2021.
- Jinming Su, Chao Chen, Ke Zhang, Junfeng Luo, Xiaoming Wei and Xiaolin Wei. Structure Guided Lane Detection. *International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)*, 2021.
- Jinming Su, Changqun Xia and Jia Li. Exploring Driving-aware Salient Object Detection via Knowledge Transfer. *IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (ICME)*, 2021. (oral)
- Jia Li, **Jinming Su**, Changqun Xia, Yonghong Tian. Distortion-adaptive Salient Object Detection in 360° Omnidirectional Images. *IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Signal Processing (J-STSP)*, 14(1), pp.38-48, 2020.
- Jinming Su, Jia Li, Yu Zhang, Changqun Xia and Yonghong Tian. Selectivity or Invariance: Boundary-aware Salient Object Detection. *IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2019.
- Jinming Su, Ruihong Yin, Xingyue Chen, Ke zhang, Junfeng Luo, Xiaoming Wei and Xiaolin Wei. Perceive, Excavate and Purify: A Novel Object Mining Framework for Instance Segmentation. (*Under Review*)
- Jinming Su, Ruihong Yin, Shuaibin Zhang, Junfeng Luo, Xiaoming Wei and Xiaolin Wei. Rethinking Consistency for Video Semantic Segmentation. (*Under Review*)

- Junwei Yang, Ke Zhang, Zhaolin Cui, **Jinming Su**, Junfeng Luo and Xiaolin Wei. InsCon:Instance Consistency Feature Representation via Self-Supervised Learning. *arXiv preprint arXiv:2203.07688*, 2022.
- Changqun Xia, Jia Li, **Jinming Su** and Yonghong Tian. Relating Background to Foreground: Exploring Reciprocal Attention for Salient Object Detection by Cooperative Learning. *arXiv* preprint arXiv:1909.08269, 2019.
- Changqun Xia, Jia Li, <u>Jinming Su</u> and Ali Borji. Learning a saliency evaluation metric using crowdsourced perceptual judgments. *arXiv preprint arXiv:1806.10257, 2018.*
- Patents: 16 items is in applications and 4 is issued (1 in the United States).

#### SKILLS

- Specialize in deep learning for computer vision
- passed CET6, good at academic writing and presentation
- Familiar with deep learning libraries Pytorch/Caffe
- Familiar with Python/Matlab/C++, Linux
- · Familiar with data structure and algorithm

## ★ PROJECTS & ACTIVITIES

- Journal reviewer of T-PAMI, T-CSVT
- Conference reviewer of CVPR, ICCV, ECCV, MIPR (PC Member)
- Teaching assistant for Machine Learning and Its Engineering Foundation at BUAA, Spring 2018
- Designed and developed the official website of CVTEAM laboratory http://cvteam.net
- Participated in the design and development of program online judge platform for NEU https://oj.neu.edu.cn
- Member of the ACM-ICPC team of NEU
- Github: https://github.com/Jinming-Su
- Old blog: https://blog.csdn.net/u014451076
- Homepage: http://jinmingsu.net

#### ■ SELECTED HONOURS

- 1st place of Corner Case Detection in the 2th SSLAD Challenge, ECCV, 2022.
- Star of Basic Research and Development Business Group (10 of 2000+), Meituan, 2022
- 5th place of Video object segmentation in the 4th Youtube-VOS Challenge, CVPR, 2022.
- Star of Intelligent Traffic Business Group (39 of 2000+), Meituan, 2021
- Outstanding Master Graduate of Beijing, 2020
- Outstanding Master Graduate Thesis of BUAA, 2020
- National Scholarship, 2019
- Huawei Scholarship, 2019
- Outstanding Student of BUAA, 2019
- Merit Student of BUAA, 2018/2019
- First Class Scholarship of Excellent Student in BUAA, 2017-2019
- Outstanding Undergraduate Thesis of NEU, 2017
- National Encouragement Scholarship, 2014-2016
- The Zhou Kun Scholarship, 2013-2016
- Excellent Student of NEU, 2014/2015
- Second Prize of the National English Competition for College Students, 2015
- First Prize of the Liaoning Province ACM-ICPC Contest, 2014/2015
- Second Prize of the China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling, 2014
- Outstanding Individual of Scientific and Technological Innovation of NEU, 2014

## **♥** More Personal Information

- Date of birth: Jan. 25, 1995
- Native place: Yuzhou City, Xuchang City, Henan Province (河南省禹州市)
- Political appearance: Member of the Communist Party of China (CPC)
- I am a good partner, able to adapt to different circumstances quickly, responsible, optimistic and easy to communicate. At the same time, I have reliable academic and engineering ability, and I am willing to solve challenging problems.